Guide to the Roy A. Phillips Papers 1911-1944
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana-Missoula
Roy A. Phillips papers
1911-1944
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 064
Phillips, Roy A.
1.4 linear feet
This collection consists primarily of diaries Roy Phillips kept as a U.S. Forest Service employee supervising St. Joe, Nez Perce, Kaniksu, and Custer national forests in Idaho and Montana.
Biographical Note
Roy A. Phillips served many years with the U. S. Forest Service. He was supervisor of the St. Joe, Nez Perce, Kaniksu and Custer National Forests. In 1942 he left the Nez Perce Forest to work at the experimental rubber plantation in California. He returned to the Forest Service after the war and retired from the Custer National Forest in 1951.
This collection contains Phillips' Forest Service diaries from April 1911 through June of 1942, as well as two handbooks, two years of memorandums and a 1941 photograph taken at a Forest Supervisors meeting in Utah.
Materials have been arranged chronologically within format.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana-Missoula.
The chain of ownership of this collection is unknown.
Information about the acquistion of this collection by the Archives has not been located.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
United States. Forest Service--Officials and employees--Diaries
Custer National Forest (Mont. and S.D.); Kaniksu National Forest; Nezperce National Forest (Idaho); Saint Joe National Forest (Idaho)
Forest reserves--Idaho; Forest reserves--Montana; Forest reserves--South Dakota; National parks and reserves--Idaho; National parks and reserves--Montana; National parks and reserves--South Dakota
Montana; Idaho; Forestry and Forestry Products
- Diary, April 1, 1911 through May 25, 1912 (Box-folder 1/1)
- Diary, July 1, 1918 through October 15, 1918 (Box-folder 1/2)
- Diary, February 3, 1919 through October 6, 1919 (Box-folder 1/3)
- Diary, December 1, 1919 through March 31, 1920, and May 1-May 5, 1920 (Box-folder 1/4)
- Diary, April 1920 (Box-folder 1/5)
- Diary, July 19, 1921 through December 31, 1921 (and possibly 1927) (Box-folder 1/6)
- Diary, January 1, 1922 through September 30, 1922 (Box-folder 1/7)
- Diary, January 1, 1923 through December 31, 1923 (and possibly 1917) (Box-folder 1/8)
- Diary, January 1, 1928 through September 21, 1928 (Box-folder 1/9)
- Diary, October 1, 1928 through August 31, 1929 (Box-folder 1/10)
- Diary, September 1, 1929 through December 2, 1929 (Box-folder 2/1)
- Diary, January 1, 1930 through June 18, 1930 (Box-folder 2/2)
- Diary, July 1, 1930 through September 30, 1930 (Box-folder 2/3)
- Diary, October 1, 1930 through January 29, 1931 (Box-folder 2/4)
- Diary, February 1, 1931 through April 30, 1931 (Box-folder 2/5)
- Diary, May 1, 1931 through September 30, 1931 (Box-folder 2/6)
- Diary, October 1, 1931 through January 31, 1932 (Box-folder 2/7)
- Diary, February 1, 1932 through September 30, 1932 (Box-folder 2/8)
- Diary, October 1, 1932 through October 27, 1933 (Box-folder 2/9)
- Diary, November 1, 1933 through October 31, 1934 (Box-folder 2/10)
- Diary, November 1, 1934 through October 31, 1935 (Box-folder 2/11)
- Diary, November 1, 1935 through February 28, 1936 (Box-folder 2/12)
- Diary, March 1, 1936 through December 31, 1936 (Box-folder 3/1)
- Diary, January 1, 1937 through December 31, 1937 (Box-folder 3/2)
- Diary, January 1, 1938 through June 30, 1939 (Box-folder 3/3)
- Diary, July 1, 1939 through June 27, 1940 (Box-folder 3/4)
- Diary, July 1, 1940 through June 30, 1942 (Box-folder 3/5)
- Miscellaneous, undated (Box-folder 3/6)
- Cattle Brands, undated (Box-folder 3/7)
- Handbook, 1920-1941 (Box-folder 3/8)
- Handbook, 1941-1944 (Box-folder 3/9)
- Memorandums, 1927 (Box-folder 3/10)
- Memorandums, 1944 (Box-folder 3/11)
- Photograph of Forest Supervisors Meeting in Ogden, Utah, 1941 (Box-folder 3/12)